Inkyu Shin | Curriculum Vitae

☑ dlsrbgg33@kaist.ac.kr

I recently received Ph.D. degree in future vehicle from the Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST), where I was co-advised by Prof. Kuk-Jin Yoon and Prof. In So Kweon. I earned my B.S and M.S degrees in automotive engineering from Hanyang University(HYU) and KAIST in 2019 and 2021. I interned at NEC Laboratories America, Inc, San Jose, CA (with Dr. Yi-Hsuan Tsai), Google Research (with Dr. Liang-Chieh Chen and Dr. Jun Xie) and recently have engaged in a research internship at ByteDance/TikTok.

Research Interests

My research is dedicated to establishing a robust foundation in the field of computer vision. This endeavor focuses on pioneering advancements in beyond or human-level visual **generation** and **recognition**, while pursuing the **data-efficiency** for generalizability. Specifically, I am interested in the following research topics:

o Learning for Generative AI

Video Generation / Editing

o Learning for Visual Recognition

Image Segmentation Video Segmentation Multiple Object Tracking Multiple Camera Tracking

Learning for Data-efficiency

Learning from Simulation Domain Adaptation Unsupervised Learning Self-supervised Learning

but also open to other explorable/challenging domains.

The ultimate purpose of this research is to apply to a variety of applications (e.g., Video synthesis, Autonomous driving, Robot navigation, AR/VR).

Research Experience

ByteDance / TikTok	San Jose, CA
Research Intern, Mentors: Liang-Chieh Chen and Qihang Yu	Sep 2023 - Jan 2024
- Topic: Video Generation / Editing	

Google Research

Student Researcher Intern, Mentors: Liang-Chieh Chen and Jun Xie

LA, CA (virtual)

May 2022 - April 2023

- Topic: Video Recognition / Tracking

NEC Laboratories America, Inc
Research Intern, Mentor: Yi-Hsuan Tsai

San Jose, CA (virtual)

May 2021 - Aug 2021

- Topic: Test-time Adaptation

Korea University
Research Intern, Supervisor: Jaegul Choo
Sep 2018 - Dec 2018

- Topic: Image-to-Image Translation

Hanyang University

Research Assistant, Supervisor: Myuong-Ho Sunwoo

Seoul, Korea *Jul 2018 - Aug 2018*

Education

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

Daejeon, Korea

Future Vehicle Ph.D. degree, Co-Advisors: Kuk-Jin Yoon and In So Kweon

2021-2024

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

Daejeon, Korea

Future Vehicle M.S degree, Advisor: In So Kweon

2019–2021

Master's Thesis: Learning to Scale the Labels for Self-training based Domain Adaptation

Hanyang University (HYU)

AUTOMOTIVE ENGINEERING B.S degree

Seoul, Korea 2013–2019

Publications

(C: conference / J: journal / P: preprint / * :equal contributions)

[P3] Enhancing Temporal Consistency in Video Editing by Reconstructing Videos with 3D Gaussian Splatting

Inkyu Shin, Qihang Yu, Xiaohui Shen, In So Kweon, Kuk-Jin Yoon, Liang-Chieh Chen arXiv, 2024

 [C14] MTMMC: A Large-Scale Real-World Multi-Modal Camera Tracking Benchmark Sanghyun Woo*, Kwanyong Park*, Inkyu Shin*, Myungchul Kim*, In So Kweon Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2024

o [C13] Video-kMaX: A Simple Unified Approach for Online and Near-Online Video Panoptic Segmentation

Inkyu Shin, Dahun Kim, Qihang Yu, Jun Xie, Hong-Seok Kim, Bradley Green, In So Kweon, Kuk-Jin Yoon, Liang-Chieh Chen

Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV), 2024 (Oral)

- Also presented at "Transformer For Vision" Workshops in conjuction with "CVPR, 2023

o [C12] MATE: Masked Autoencoders are Online 3D Test-Time Learners

Muhammad Jehanzeb Mirza*, Inkyu Shin*, Wei Lin*, Andreas Schriebl, Kunyang Sun, Jaesung Choe,
Horst Possegger, Mateusz Kozinski, In So Kweon, Kuk-Jin Yoon, Horst Bischof

o [C11] TTA-COPE: Test-Time Adaptation for Category-Level Object Pose Estimation

Taeyeop Lee, Jonathan Tremblay, Valts Blukis, Bowen Wen, Byeong-Uk Lee, **Inkyu Shin**, Stan Birchfield, In So Kweon, Kuk-Jin Yoon

Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2023

International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV), 2023

[C10] Bidirectional Domain Mixup for Domain Adaptive Semantic Segmentation
Daehan Kim*, Minseok Seo*, Kwanyong Park, Inkyu Shin, Sanghyun Woo
Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2023

 [C9] Learning Classifiers of Prototypes and Reciprocal Points for Universal Domain Adaptation Sungsu Hur, Inkyu Shin, Kwanyong Park, Sanghyun Woo, In So Kweon Winter Conference on Computer Vision (WACV), 2023

[C8] Moving from 2D to 3D: volumetric medical image classification for rectal cancer staging

Joohyung Lee*, Jieun Oh*, **Inkyu Shin**, You-sung Kim, Dae Kyung Sohn, Tae-sung Kim, In So Kweon Medical Image Computing and Computer Assisted Intervention (**MICCAI**), 2023

 [C7] MM-TTA: Multi-Modal Test-Time Adaptation for 3D Semantic Segmentation Inkyu Shin, Yi-Hsuan Tsai, Bingbing Zhuang, Samuel Schulter, Buyu Liu, Sparsh Garg, In So Kweon, Kuk-Jin Yoon

Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2022

- Received Qualcomm Innovation Award 2022.
- o [C6] UDA-COPE: Unsupervised Domain Adaptation for Category-level Object Pose Estimation Taeyeop Lee, Byeong-Uk Lee, Inkyu Shin, Jaesung Choe, Ukcheol Shin, In So Kweon, Kuk-Jin Yoon Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2022
- [P2] Unsupervised Domain Adaptation for Video Semantic Segmentation Kwanyong Park*, Inkyu Shin*, Sanghyun Woo, In So Kweon arXiv, 2021
- [C5] LabOR: Labeling Only if Required for Domain Adaptive Semantic Segmentation Inkyu Shin, Dong-Jin Kim, Jae Won Cho, Sanghyun Woo, Kwanyong Park, In So Kweon International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV), 2021 (Oral)
 - Received Qualcomm Innovation Award 2021.
- [P1] Learning Representations by Contrasting Clusters While Bootstrapping Instances
 Junsoo Lee, Hojoon Lee, Inkyu Shin, Jaekyoung Bae, In So Kweon, Jaegul Choo
 arXiv. 2020
- [C4] Discover, Hallucinate, and Adapt:
 Open Compound Domain Adaptation for Semantic Segmentation
 Kwanyong Park, Sanghyun Woo, Inkyu Shin, In So Kweon
 Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2020
 - Received Qualcomm Innovation Award 2021.
- [C3] Two-phase Pseudo Label Densification for Self-training based Domain Adaptation Inkyu Shin, Sanghyun Woo, Fei pan, In So Kweon European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2020
 - Also presented at "Visual Learning with Limited Labels" Workshops in conjunction with (CVPR), 2020
- [C2] Unsupervised Intra-domain Adaptation for Semantic Segmentation through Self-Supervision
 Fei pan, Inkyu Shin, Francois Rameau, Seokju Lee, In So Kweon
 Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2020 (Oral)
 - Received Qualcomm Innovation Award 2020.
- o [C1] Image-to-Image Translation via Group-wise Deep Whitening-and-Coloring Transformation Wonwoong Cho, Sungha Choi, David Keetae Park, Inkyu Shin, Jaegul Choo Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2019 (Oral)

Professtional Activities

Conference Reviewer

o CVPR (2022~), ICCV (2023~), NeurIPS (2021~), ICML (2022~)

Awards

- o 2022: Qualcomm Innovation Award
- o 2021: Qualcomm Innovation Award
- o 2020: Qualcomm Innovation Award

IT Skills

- o Languages: Python, MATLAB, C, LATEX
- o Libraries: PyTorch, TensorFlow

Military Service

- o KATUSA at 8th Army, U.S. Army
 - Discharged as a Sergeant
 - Graduated WLC (Sergeant School of U.S. Army) as 7th in rank

References

o Prof. In So Kweon

Relationship: M.S & Ph.D Advisor Professor, Electrical Engineering, KAIST

Email: iskweon77@kaist.ac.kr

o Prof. Kuk-Jin Yoon

Relationship: Ph.D Advisor

Professor, Mechanical Engineering, KAIST

Email: kjyoon@kaist.ac.kr

o Dr. Yi-Hsuan Tsai

Relationship: Internship mentor at NEC Lab. (Previous) Research scientist, NEC Lab. (Current) AI/ML Tech Lead Manager, Google

Email: wasidennis@gmail.com

o Dr. Liang-Chieh Chen

Relationship: Internship mentor at Google Research / ByteDance

(Previous) Research scientist, Google Research (Current) Research scientist, ByteDance

Email: lcchen@cs.ucla.edu